<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <XenotypeDef>
    <defName>DV_Avaloi</defName>
    <label>avaloi</label>
    <description>The Avaloi are extremely psychically sensitive humans adapted to their low-grav glitterworld, whose technology has practically eliminated both pollution and natural predators. However, the lack of environmental stressors has made them maladapted to the wider galaxy, leaving them with brittle bones and delicate skin that take longer to heal. This very skin, though colorful, has increased pain sensitivity and porosity, making them vulnerable to the very pollution their civilization has vanquished. They sport an impressively complex nervous system, which is particularly well adapted to psychic influences and the acquisition of new knowledge, and the unique ability to acquire even more sensitivity to psychic phenomena by drinking alcoholic beverages.\n\nThese features have transformed the Avaloi into a philosopher society, whose alcohol addiction and intellectualism have combined into great raves on topics such as metaphysics and ethics. Their origins are a common topic of legends and stories, for only a few people know of the rich and vast glitterworlds in the core of the galaxy which house the most disgustingly wealthy of the human race, and technology capable of changing the body in any way they desire, even for simple trends and fashion. Perhaps the Avaloi are one such group of people who have never changed back from these fast fashion choices, or perhaps they're a unique xenotype birthed by the marriage of man and archotech god, not unlike the ancient greek myths. In truth, they're one of many xenotypes born from the comfortable conditions on coreworlds, where they enjoy lives with little to no labor that revolve entirely around art, philosophy, and pleasure.</description>
    <descriptionShort>The Avaloi are extremely psychically sensitive humans adapted to their low-grav glitterworld, whose technology has practically eliminated both pollution and natural predators. However, the lack of environmental stressors has made them maladapted to the wider galaxy, leaving them with brittle bones and delicate skin that take longer to heal. This very skin, though colorful, has increased pain sensitivity and porosity, making them vulnerable to the very pollution their civilization has vanquished. They sport an impressively complex nervous system, which is particularly well adapted to psychic influences and the acquisition of new knowledge, and the unique ability to acquire even more sensitivity to psychic phenomena by drinking alcoholic beverages.</descriptionShort>
    <iconPath>UI/Xenotypes/Avaloi</iconPath>
    <inheritable>true</inheritable>
    <genes>
    <li>Body_Thin</li>
    <li>PsychicAbility_Enhanced</li>
    <li>WoundHealing_Slow</li>
    <li>Aggression_DeadCalm</li>
    <li>Learning_Fast</li>
    <li>Beauty_Pretty</li>
    <li>Libido_High</li>
    <li>ChemicalDependency_Alcohol</li>
    <li>AptitudeStrong_Artistic</li>
    <li>AptitudeStrong_Intellectual</li>
    <li>DV_ToxResist_Terrible</li>
    <li>DV_PsychicInebriation</li>
    <li>Immunity_Weak</li>
	  <li>DV_Head_Avaloi</li>
	  <li>DV_Coral_Antlers</li>
    <li>DV_Coral_Beards</li>
    <li>Hair_BaldOnly</li>
    <li>Beard_NoBeardOnly</li>
    <li>Skin_SoftBlue</li>
    <li>Skin_SoftYellow</li>
    <li>Skin_SoftGreen</li>
    <li>Skin_SoftPink</li>
    <li>Skin_SoftRed</li>
    <li>DV_AvaloiHairColors</li>
    <li>Hair_Grayless</li>
    </genes>
  </XenotypeDef>

</Defs>
